<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World! on Deborah Popoola</title>
    <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello World! on Deborah Popoola</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/about/</guid>
      <description>Unraveling complex data is my forte. Using SQL, Python, and Power BI, I navigate disparate sources, uncover hidden patterns, and build predictive models that solve real-world challenges. Fueled by curiosity and continuous learning, I&amp;rsquo;m a highly motivated data professional eager to blend meticulous analysis with innovative problem-solving. I&amp;rsquo;m your ideal partner for transforming data into actionable strategies and evolving to meet your needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/contact/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Connect on these platforms&#xA;linkedIn:| https://www.linkedin.com/in/deborahpopoola github:| https://github.com/Popsonn mail:| deborahopepopoola@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiochemRAG: Domain-Specific Biochemistry RAG System</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/biochem-rag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/biochem-rag/</guid>
      <description>Developed a specialized Retrieval-Augmented Generation system for biochemistry education, targeting amino acid and nucleotide biosynthesis from Lehninger Principles of Biochemistry. Built with Mistral-7B-Instruct, sentence-transformers, and ChromaDB for semantic search and scientifically accurate response generation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria Incidence Rate Predictive Model</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/malaria-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/malaria-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Developed an advanced machine learning model to predict malaria incidence rates across Africa as part of Team GitLab "The Visionaries" during Hamoye internship. Conducted spatial analysis using Global Moran's statistics, integrated population-based metrics, and achieved high R² scores to enable proactive outbreak prediction and precision-targeted control strategies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Agent Adverse Media Screening System for FATF Compliance</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/adverse-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/adverse-media/</guid>
      <description>Developed a sophisticated multi-agent LLM system for financial crime compliance, featuring four specialized agents for entity disambiguation, search strategy, classification, and conflict resolution. Built with DSPy framework, integrates dual-LLM validation and follows FATF taxonomy for comprehensive adverse media screening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Data Cleaning in Python</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/food-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/food-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Built a conversational AI assistant using Rasa framework with natural language understanding capabilities. Integrated with Spoonacular API for recipe search, nutritional analysis, meal planning, and wine pairing suggestions. Deployed on Slack for seamless workplace accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Text Summarization with Fine-tuned BART</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/text-summarisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/text-summarisation/</guid>
      <description>Fine-tuned Facebook's BART-large-CNN model for domain-specific text summarization using custom dataset. Implemented end-to-end pipeline including data preprocessing, model fine-tuning with Hugging Face Transformers, and evaluation on 100 test samples with optimized generation parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepseek-R1-Distill-Llama-70b RAG System for Mental Health Research</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/mental-health-rag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/mental-health-rag/</guid>
      <description>Developed a specialized Retrieval-Augmented Generation system leveraging Deepseek-R1-Distill-Llama-70b to analyze 504,913 PubMed articles on suicide, mental health, and depression. Built with HuggingFace embeddings, FAISS vector storage, and advanced LLM integration to provide evidence-based insights for researchers, clinicians, and policymakers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 7: Telco Customer Churn</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on a journey to understand and tackle customer churn, I delved into the realm of telecommunications data armed with Excel for meticulous analysis and Power BI for compelling visualization. This project aimed to uncover patterns, identify key factors influencing customer churn, and pave the way for strategic interventions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 8: Olist E-commerce Analysis</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Unlocking Insights for Growth: Delved into the Olist sales dataset to provide valuable answers to crucial business questions. From total revenue trends to product categories, customer behaviors, and marketing strategy optimization, this analysis aimed to empower Olist with actionable insights for e-commerce success.&#xA;link to github repository</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 9: Movies Rental Business Acquisition Analysis</title>
      <link>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Popsonn.github.io/deborahpopoola/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Using advanced SQL skills, I navigated the Movies Database, crafting multi-table queries to unveil crucial insights. This project showcases my ability to extract and analyze data systematically, providing valuable information essential for informed decision-making in the acquisition process.&#xA;link to github repository</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
